Partial Inventory of the Carl Frederick Eifler papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Carl Frederick Eifler papers
1934-2001
2002C74
Hoover Institution Archives
6 manuscript boxes, 51 motion picture film reels (7.6 linear feet)
Orders, reports, personnel records, correspondence, writings, printed matter, photographs, and motion picture film relating to Office of Strategic Services sabotage and espionage operations in the China-Burma-India Theater during World War II. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Eifler, Carl F. (Carl Frederick), 1906-
Access
Collection is open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2002.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Biographical Note
Colonel, United States Army; commanding officer, Detachment 101, Office of Strategic Services, 1942-1945.
Scope and Content of Collection
Orders, reports, personnel records, correspondence, writings, printed matter, photographs, and motion picture film relating to Office of Strategic Services sabotage and espionage operations in the China-Burma-India Theater during World War II.
United States. Office of Strategic Services.; World War, 1939-1945--Secret service.; Secret service--United States.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Burma.; Motion pictures.
- Not yet described (Boxes 1-6)
- Declassified U.S. Government Records, 1942-1945
  Scope and Contents note
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Available as PDF files. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover, thereunder chronologically by date of creation.
  - 2017 release of records, 1942-1945 (Reading room workstation)
    - Orders, memos, cables, accounts, and other records regarding mission in China-Burma-India theater, 1942 May - 1945 September
    - Official dispatch from the Office of Strategic Services to Ustravic, London, re request from MacArthur for officers to teach sabotage to Philippine guerillas, 1944 May 22
    - Reports and other records regarding activities on Catalina Island, Howland's and Johnson's Landings, and Gimicks, 1945 February - July
    - Napko Project plan, with related OSS Research & Analysis Branch reports on Korea, 1945 March
- Motion Picture Film, 51 motion picture film reels (Film shelf)
  Titles taken from film cans.
  - Untitled, 16mm film, 6 motion picture film reels
  - "Col Eifler Scenes Not Used," 16mm film
  - "Trip to Seagraves - Plane crash - Dead in," 16mm film
  - "5 Neg. (Some Catalina) Peers Wife & Kids," 16mm film
  - "9," 16mm film
  - "12 Nazira O Camp Etc.," 16mm film
  - "1 Gen Donovan," 16mm film
  - "4," 16mm film
  - "7 Neg. - D.C. - Lou Negative Film," 16mm film
  - "3 No Good 11-86," 16mm film
  - "2 Chittagong Rescue," 16mm film
  - "13 Color India ___ Cairo Anzio-London #2 of 3rd," 16mm film
  - "4 Eifler/Coughlin 1st Burma Entry Sumpro," 16mm film
  - "6," 16mm film
  - "8 Carls Family Wilckies Family Careful Editing," 16mm film
  - "9 Hawaii Scenes," 16mm film
  - "U23 6894 KO," 16mm film
  - "14-22," 16mm film
  - "23-29," 16mm film
  - "10-13," 16mm film
  - "11," 16mm film
  - "5-6," 16mm film, 2 motion picture film reels
  - "SP3424 Neg," 16mm film
  - "2-3," 16mm film, 2 motion picture film reels
  - "10 Catalina 2 Man Sub," 16mm film
  - "From Pearl Harbour," 16mm film, 19 motion picture film reels